and you need to focus on
а тебе нужно ориентироваться на
Soviet education like the Soviet
Советское образование вот как Советское
Soviet education in schools Yes, it was
Советское образование в школах Да оно
considered the best in the world, do
считалось самое лучшее в мире вот знаешь
you know the first element of the periodic table
ли ты первый элемент таблицы Менделеева
Oh there Aum, in my opinion Au is right Yes, and how
Ой там Аум по-моему Ау правильно Да а
many cases are there in the Russian language
падежей в русском языке сколько
Oh Ivan gave birth to a girl, ordered to drag a
Ой Иван родил девчонку велел тащить
diaper,
пелёнку
nominative Ivan di
именительный Иван ди
di iva
ди ива
di Ivan gave birth to a girl named Rodite
ди Иван родил девчонку имени Родите
dattel Hello, something is wrong with your Internet
датель Привет что-то У тебя Интернет
or mine Everything is fine with me It's cool where are
тормозит или у меня У меня всё нормально
you from What movie are you from No, I'm
до Прикольно ты откуда Из какого фильма
not from a movie I'm from life Let's
Да не я не из фильма Я из жизни Давай
get to know each other first Let's My name is
познакомимся для начала Давай Меня зовут
Kirill from Chelyabinsk Where are you from
Кирил из Челябинска Ты откуда будешь
I'm telling you Your Internet is slow Well, earn
Я же говорю У тебя Интернет тупит Ну
a little extra money
чуть-чуть подзаработать
BN are you from Star Wars or something like that, the nature of the rings is
БН ты со Звёздных войн что ли
even worse
колец ещё
[music]
[музыка]
Listen, I've never watched
хлеще Слушай вот ни разу не смотрел
Imagine Not a single
Прикинь Ни одной
episode of these Star Wars and The Lord of the
серии этих Звёздных войн и Властелин
Rings, maybe I watched the
колец может
first part, maybe I watched it from
быть первую часть может быть смотрел от
beginning to end, maybe I had to
начала до конца может быть пришлось
somehow there Do
как-то там
n't look don't look Yes no no do
Не смотри не смотри Да не
n't look it's better to live in reality
не не смотри лучше жить в реальности
I understand than in
понял чем в
Nama or or in an imposed reality
Нама или или в навязанной реальности
you know there is
знаешь
Agree yes Well tell me at
есть Согласись да Ну скажи город-то хотя
least what kind of city I told you
бы какой я же сказал
TF I mean there is such a city Where is this Yes
ТФ В смысле такой город есть Это где Да
in Ukraine they built such a
в Украине построили городок такой
tourist town here like All the houses there are
туристический у нас типа Там все домики
in the form of the
в виде
Hobbit based on yes Yes no no
Хоббита по мотивам да Да не ну не ну
seriously in the Ivano-Frankivsk region I
серьёзно в ивано-франковской области Я
bought Yes there is this house and we live Well so well
купил Да там домик этот и живём А ну так
Ivanov frak sea region Well yes the
вот ну Иванов фрак морская область Ну да
city Hobbit Vil everything is a village and the Ivano-
город Хоббит Виль всё деревня а Ивано
Frankivsk region it is closer where it is
Франковская область она ближе куда
located uh near Donetsk from Lugansk the
находится э возле Донецка с Луганска
border is here so
гранич сюда
soon this soon the
находится так уже скоро этот уже скоро
border is approaching so it turns out it turns out
граница подходит значит
about the World Cup I am talking Well
получается о ЧМ я общаюсь
look You yourself understand that now the
смотри Ты же сам понимаешь что сейчас
most painful topic is what about this svobod
самая наболевшее тема о чём об это сво
Yes but I can talk to you about any topic
Да но я могу на любые темы с тобой
let's say let's
пообщаться допустим давай о тачках
talk about cars What car are you driving Come on
пообщаемся Ты на какой тачке едешь Давай
look come on I I  I don't understand anything about
смотри давай я Я не разбираюсь вообще в
them
тах
I'm sad myself I'm
я сам
interested do you know which one is the
уны мне интересно вот ты знаешь какой
first
первы переть
What field of science are you in I'm a Chemist I'm a Chemist
какой сфере науки ты я Химик я Химик
Chemist just for fun I do polls on
Химик вот ради интереса Я делаю опросы в
chatroulette how do you know do you know the first
чатрулет как ты знаешь ли ты первый
element of the
элемент табли
periodic table why Au That's right I don't
Менделеева пому Ау Правильно точно не
remember exactly in short Au it starts with the letter a The first
помню короче Ау он на букву а Первый
element Ani pa Alpha Well it's not a fact that it's the first You see it's the first first
элемент Ани па Алфа Ну не факт что он
Aum yes It's
первый Понимаешь он первый первый Аум да
not a fact that it's the first After it
Не факт что он первый После него
comes only Argentum Well it's not a fact Well I I
Аргентум идёт только Ну не факт Ну я я
can't tell you for sure but what
точно тебе не могу сказать но что что на
comes to mind I'm telling you I understand there is a
ум приходит вот я тебе говорю понял
little bit of photographic memory but
фотографическая память есть чуть-чуть но
maybe it is like that Well in short
может быть оно так и есть Ну короче
photographic auram you remember
фотографический аурам ты помнишь
photographic Remember Aum Yes telny
фотографический Помнишь Аум Да тельный
Reflex to Aum worked yes I understood
Рефлекс на Аум работал да понял
and a What is the formula of carbon dioxide CO2
и а Какая формула углекислого газа CO2
there I don't know know Well it's It's like CO2 - it's
там я не знаю зна Ну это Это типа CO2 -
not complete but complete no I won't tell
это он не полный а полный не не скажу
you CO3 Well maybe I'll tell you Well I'm
тебе CO3 Ну может быть я тебе Ну в этом
not good at that honestly
я не силён честно
[music]
[музыка]
and look
и смотри
e What is your  interest to know if I'm
э В чём заключается твой интерес узнать
good at it or not I'm good in Good question good
нет Я хороший во Хороший вопрос хороши
Good question Yes I'm a member of the
Хороший вопрос Да я э вхожу в состав
ministerial commission on developing
министерской комиссии по разработке
curricula for schoolchildren on
э учебных планов для школьников по
teaching chemistry and we have discussions about
обучению химии и у нас идут дискуссии
whether or not to study chemistry in such a
стоит или не стоит изучать химии в таком
volume I say that
объёме Я говорю что
We have very weak knowledge of chemistry that people,
У нас очень слабые знания химии что люди
for example, do not even know the first element of the
например даже не знают первый элемент
periodic table here are the older generation the
таблицы Менделеева вот старшее поле
older generation like you Aum say
старшие поколение как ты Аум говорят
normal But now students those per immediately you the
норм А вот уже студенты те пере сразу
answer immediately interrupted you it is possible yes I
ответ сразу тебя перебил можно да я
think it is worth it you know why why And
считаю что стоит знаешь почему почему А
you need to focus on Soviet
тебе нужно ориентироваться на Советское
education like in the Soviet Soviet
образование вот как в советско Советское
education in schools was it was considered the
образование в школах было оно считалось
best in the world Here you What
самае лучшее в мире Вот ты Ты какого
year were you born What year were you born in the
года рождения Ты какого года рождения
first year I was eighty-first
воем первого года я восемьдесят первого
By the way, yes you are still Yes you are still 4 years old about
Кстати да ты ещё Да ты 4 года ещё про
Soviet education etc. Here is the
Советском образования прочи Вот и
Soviet bazaar By the way,
Советская базаром был Ещё между прочим
what about look You see how long you have
причём смотри Ты видишь уже сколько уже
not studied at school but every Soviet
не учишься в школе но каждый Советский
schoolboy woke him up ask the first
школьник его разбудил спроси первый
element blitz Mile he will say aura yes yes you
элемент блиц Миле он скажет ауру да да
understand this this this this A priori
понимаешь это это это это это Априори
you understand
понимаешь
but this this  some foreign word
но это это какое-то иностранное слово
A priori what does it mean A priori it was
Априори что это озна Априори считалось
always considered that Soviet
всегда что Советское
A priori is a proven fact A priori is a
Априори это доказанный факт Априори это
proven fact yes Well, well, in my opinion Well,
доказанный факт да Ну ято ну по моим Ну
I just know there is a Lada and a Priora And
я просто знаю вот есть Лада а Приора А
what is a priori no A priori is this this is something
что такое априори нет Априори это это
else this What language is
другое это Это на каком языке вообще
A priori in general Well, forget it in Google, look there
Априори Ну ты Забей в Гугле посмотри там
I just didn't understand Well, you said this
я просто не понял Ну ты же это сказал
word joke yes I told you A priori is That is, a
слово шутка да Я тебе сказал Априори это
proven fact of that I know I
То бишь доказанный факт того я знаю я
know khachapuri well A priori USA friend this well come on well
хачапури знаю ну Априори США друг это ну
in reality either you well are you trolling
давай ну в натуре или ты ну троллишь
me or we I'm not trolling I'm not me This is the first time I've
меня или мы Я не троллю я не я Впервые
heard such a word A priori It can't be it can't be
слышу такое слово Априори Не может
here
такого быть не может такого быть у нас
in Ukraine How many subscribers How many
на Украи Сколько подписчиков Сколько
subscribers are there now watching nobody watching
подписчиков смотрит никто не смотрит
just
просто
chatting friend Well, look, damn
общаюсь друг Ну смотри
Come on, I'll just bend my topic
Давай я буду свою тему просто гнуть
A priori is a proven
Априори - это значит доказанный
fact you understood everything a proven
факт те всё понял доказанный
fact it is recognized in the whole society that well,
факт это признанное в всем обществом то
we are specifically talking now  about
что ну мы конкретно сейчас говорим о
soviet education correctly
советском образовании правильно
soviet education was the best
Советское образование Было самое лучшее
in the world and still is who decided so who decided
в мире и до сих Кто так решил Кто решил
and still thinks so all society yes
и до сих пор считает Да всё общество Да
you num is considered
ты нум считается
yes even if we
Да вот даже если
take the
взять
average soviet
среднестатистического советского
schoolchild yes you and take the
школьника Да вот тебя и взять средне
average american schoolchild
статистического американского школьника
pony and compare one year and one time
Пони и Сравни одни года и одно время
how much they spent in school well and
сколько они провели в школе Ну и
look at knowledge you know by the way
посмотреть знания понимаешь А кстати
how many in russian here i know how many
сколько вот в русском вот Я знаю сколько
in the ukrainian alphabet how many
в украинском алфавите А сколько в
letters are in the russian alphabet oh damn well
русском алфавите букв Ой блин ну что
stop it i'm just curious how
завязывай не мне просто интересно как
sko well good in nature not how many
ско Ну хорош в натуре не то сколько ВМ
letters in the VM alphabet well
алфавите букв Ну ну
seriously do you know do you know how many
серьёзно знаешь А ты знаешь сколько было
letters were in the russian alphabet before peter the great there were
в русском алфавите букв до Петра I там
something like 70 or 80
что-то 70 или 80
it 47 47 super yes and now modern
ИТ 47 47 супер да А сечас современно
soviet no no 33 how many teeth 32 oh maybe i made a
Советской не не 33 как зубов 32 о может
mistake less yes 32 well one vi is correct
ошибся меньше Да 32 Ну один ви правильно
yes and how many cases are there in the russian language
Да а падежей в русском языке
Ivan gave birth to a girl ordered to drag a
сколько Иван родил девчонку велел тащить
diaper
пелёнку
nominative Ivan
именительный Иван
gave birth to a ditel dative  ordered accusative to
родил дитель дательный велел винительный
drag to drag on T what instrumental to
тащить тащить на Т какой творительный
drag a diaper a diaper is on p what Well
тащить пелёнку пелёнка - это на п какой
I got it No no what on
Ну понял Нет нет какой на
p
п
prepositional what prepositional case
предложный что предложный подеж
prepositional cool Yeah Ivan gave birth to a
предложный прикольно Угу Иван родил
girl saw to drag a diaper you understand b
девчонку видел тащить пелёнку понимаешь
Cool that's all
б Прикольно вот и всё
[music]
[музыка]
Well a priori case yes a priori case Yes no no not
Ну априорный подеж да априорный подеж Да
a priori but prepositional you
не не не априорный а предложный
understand That's all And what is it called
понимаешь Вот и всё А что он называется
prepositional is to offer you and he
предложный это тебе предлагать а он
probably offers something to everyone Yes I
что-то предлагает наверное каждому Да я
he offers drank knows why they
он предлагает пил знает почему его так
called him that And on What question does it answer
называли А на На какой вопрос отвечает
Here is a nominative - this is who What And a
Вот именительный - это кто Что А
prepositional is well whom whom what whom what
предложный - это ну
this genitive
кого кого чего кого чего это родительный
no genitive this is a parent gave birth to whom what you
нет родительный это родитель родил кого
understand no whom what this
что понимаешь не кого что это
accusative gave birth to whom what no Look who what this well what what who
винительный родил кого что нет Смотри
genitive pony who what this accusative And who what this
кого что это винительный А кого чего это
parent what who difference no one
родитель что кого разница никого ещё раз
look again what who this here I see who I
смотри что кого это вот я вижу кого я
need I'm not me
надо я не я
advice I'm testing  the best I test the
совет я тестирую лучши я тестирую самые
best Soviet education You
лучшее Советское образование Вот тебе
need this look I just remember I still
это надо смотри я просто помню я ещё 4
had 4 years of Soviet education
года советского образования застал
Russian language genitive is who what
русский язык родительный это кого чего
accusative is the fourth this is who
винительный - это четвёртой это вот кого
what I see who I see what it is I
что я вижу кого я вижу что
will not argue with you now well
это я с тобой не буду спорить я сейчас
as if I do not want to go into these
ну как бы я не хочу вдаваться в Эти
details Why Because I am
подробности Почему Потому что меня один
interested in one question to you now in our
вопрос интересует тебе сейчас в нашем
dialogue Why do you need to find out all this I
диалоге Для чего нужно это всё выяснять
know wait wait wait I am not I have not finished
знаю стой стой стой я не я не закончил
You listen to the question the question is correct
Ты послушай вопрос вопрос правильный
Listen to you in our dialogue why do you need to
Послушай тебе в нашем диалоге для чего
find out do I know this or not I will explain
это выяснять знаю я это или нет объясню
I am studying What percentage of
я Я изучаю Какое процентное соотношение
knowledge remains with Soviet schoolchildren
знаний остаётся у советских школьников
after a certain number of years By
через определённое количество лет Вот
the way, how do you think how much is 1%
кстати как ты считаешь сколько будет 1%
of 100
от 100
Well Seriously or what Yes Well come on
Ну Серьёзно что ли
how much is 1% of 100 I dont
хорош давай сколько будет 1% от 100 Я не
want to answer this question just
хочу отвечать на этот вопрос просто
tell me the last Why nya opinion
скажи мне последний Почему ня мнение
Because you are now sitting trolling
Потому что ты сейчас сидишь троллишь
me but why do you need this I just
меня но для чего тебе это надо я просто
like me Ro I just  pile from 100 Du of
как я Ро Я просто сваю от 100 Ду
Soviet education tell me how much is
советского образования скажи сколько
1% of
будет 1% от
100 I will not tell you this here is 1%
100 я не буду тебе это говорить вот 1%
of 100 rubles tell me about the great Soviet
от 100 руб скажи мне о великий Советский
student Pioneer product of the best
ученик Пионер продукт лучшего
education in the world tell me how much is
образования в мире скажи сколько будет
1% of 100
1% от 100
rubles I mean from 100 rubles 1% of 100 or 1%
руб в смысле от 100 руб 1% от 100 или 1%
of 100 rubles there is a difference any tell me
от 100 руб есть разница любое скажи
tell me and how much is 1% of 100 and
скажи и сколько будет 1% от 100 и
how much is 1%
сколько будет 1% от 100 руб
of 100 rubles And how much is 1% of 100 Yes how much will it be it will be
будет 1% от 100 Да сколько это будет это
1% of 100 you
1% от
understand no that's all that's all you
100 понимаешь нет вот и всё вот и всё
understand 1% of 100 it will be 1% of 100
понимаешь 1% от 100 это будет 1% от 100
you understand That's all Do what you want with
понимаешь Вот и всё Делай что хочешь с
this cunning cunning yes
этим хитро хитро да
Yes got out got out yes education you
Да выкрутился выкрутился дае образование
understand [ __ ] she teaches the distance from the
понимаешь Бля она же учит расстояние от
Earth to the Moon is equal to the distance from the Earth
Земли до Луны равно расстояни от Земли
to the Moon yes yes cunning
до Луны да да хитро
cunning on the moon Americans only yes
хитро на луно тали американцы только да
yes the capital of France yes it is the capital of
да столица Франции да это столица
France yes he knows Soviet education
Франции да шарит Советское образование
taught And soon it will be the capital of France
научило А скоро будет столица Франции
Moscow is in the know no
Москва в курсе нет
[laughter]
[смех]
Okay the capital of France is not Moscow
Ладно столица Франции не Москва
Saint Petersburg s And by the way yes I
санкт-петербург с А вот кстати да
wonder how much I studied mathematics in
Интересно насколько я математику по
Russian in the Soviet Union And I
русский язык в Советском Союзе изучали А
wonder about geography what is the capital of
вот интересно о географии какая столица
Norway
Норвегии
oh knows I don't know os and
ой знает Не знаю ос а
Finland this what's it's called Helsinki
Финляндии этот как его Хельсинки
Cool Cool you have so many
Прикольно Прикольно у тебя столько
interjections like interesting and the capital of
междометий типа интересны а столица
Slovakia I don't know and Hungary the
Словакии не знаю а Венгрии
capital of Hungary is some kind of there I know
столица Венгрии какая-нибудь там зна
Hungary I understand I understand it
Венгрия понял понял
will be Moscow Soon we will also take over everyone
будет Москва Скоро тоже всех захватим
Soviet geography is a little better than
Советская география немножко лучше чем
Soviet mathematics and much better
Советская математика и порядком лучше
than the Soviet Russian language yes It's not a fact
чем Советский русский язык да Не факт Ты
Why are you basing your
почему на одном мне ты это строишь
conclusions on me alone you understand I'm the only one like that
выводы понимаешь это я один человек
And maybe now you'll
такой А может быть сейчас ты ещё с
talk to another ten they'll give you the whole database you
десяток пообщаешься тебе базу всю
understand well it's not a fact why do you
выдадут понимаешь ну не факт же почему
me on one Because you are just an
на одном мнет Потому что ты есть как раз
average person right
среднестатистический
here's a portrait if a portrait of a
пря вот портрет вот если портрет
Soviet schoolchild who grew up in
советского школьника который вырос в
Russia this you will be In vain  you
России вот это ты будешь Зря ты так
say so Well because g big spread
говоришь Ну потому что г большой разбег
big because you understand spread
большой потому что понимаешь разбег
big very very big Look come on
большой очень сильно большой Смотри вот
look to say so you need to
давай смотри чтобы так говорить это надо
take all the Soviet students understand and from
взять всех учеников советских понял и из
them derive the average A wait That is to say you
них вывести сред А подожди То есть ты
just told me so simply the
мне только что настолько просто
average Russian student
среднестатистический русский ученик
Soviet best American And now you
Советский лучший американского А теперь
need to calculate something derive no look look
надо что-то считать вывести нет смотри
why did I tell you you need to
смотри почему я тебе говорил надо
compare with someone right you need to
сравнивать же с кем-то правильно надо
compare with another country you also need to
сравнивать с другой страной надо также
take all all the students in another country you
взять в другой стране всех всех учеников
understand
понимаешь
first derive this average from them
сначала у них вывести этот
then derive the
среднестатистический потом у нас вывести
average from us you need to take all the
среднестатистический это надо взять всех
students you understand you know to do this
учеников понимаешь жешь заняться этой
work And how did you get down to ska sove soze lu
работой А как ты занялся ска сове созе
che it is recognized understand Who took all these
че это признан понима Кто взял этих всех
students No it is recognized in
учеников Нет это признан
this recognized by whom
этом признано кем
recognized wait wait I
признано подожди стой я же тебе
told you Initially it was not recognized by
Изначально сказал что это признано не
me in the whole world a
мной во всм мире
sign recognized who recognized Oxford
признак признал кто признал Оксфорд
their students Compare with ours their
их учеников Сравни с нашими их
graduates take Let's take let's take let's sum Circle
выпускников возьми Давай возм давай сум
good Susie Circle Let's take
Круг хорошо Сузи Круг Давай возьмём
some year there, let's say, the year of
какой-нибудь год там допустим там год
birth That's right Yes In the first year, let's take
рождения Вот правильно Да Во пер год
Oxford
возьмём да возьмём выпускников оксфорда
Harvard graduates and take GU IGO-GO graduates
гарварда и возьмём выпускников гу иго-го
in knowledge Yes Well, imagine How much
по знаниям да Ну прикинь Это насколько
work is this on Yes, that's interesting Look, yes,
это работу на Да вот интересно Смотри да
graduates of Western universities
выпускники западных университетов
created the Internet, create telephones Yes, they
создали интернет создают телефоны Да
create Starlin Yes and so on And what did
создают старлин Да и так дальше А что
graduates of the Soviet this
вот выпускники советского этого
education create over the last 30 years
образования создали за последние 30 лет
in the know And are you aware that the first cell
в курсе А ты в курсе что первый сотовый
phone in the Soviet Union was created No, it's
телефон в Советском Союзе был создан Нет
not true Well, how even is this a
неправда Ну как даже это это
recorded fact between everyone this is a recorded fact
зафиксированный факт между всеми это
this is there with this is a lie where and when in
это там со это это брехня где и когда в
what fact this is a recorded fact
какой фак это зафиксированный факт
Listen, in general, a recorded fact I'll
Слушай вообще зафиксированный факт я
tell you when the Soviet Union was
тебе скажу когда Советский Союз
collapsing, the majority of the population did not
распадался у большинства населения не
have a landline telephone Not to mention a
было проводного телефона Не говоря уже о
cell phone, we saw cell phones
сотовом сотовые телефоны мы увидели
after the collapse of the Soviet Union years later
после распада Советского Союза лет через
because there was no technology to
потому что не было технологий чтобы их
distribute them and samples they were you
распространить а образцы они были
understand the first computer Who invented
понимаешь первый компьютер Кто придумал
everything is also
всё тоже
Russian Well, read history you understand that
руский Ну ну ты почитай историю понял то
is, the Soviet Union was the first to invent a
есть Советский Союз первым придумал
cell phone the first to invent a
сотовый телефон первым придумал
computer they all  they came up with something but they didn't
компьютер они всё придумали но ничего не
do anything yeah Because there was no point in it
делали да Так потому что в этом Смысла
you know and not only there was no point there was no
не было понимаешь и не то что Смысла не
way to spread
было не было возможности распространить
it you know that is they came up with something they
это понима то есть они придумали они
always came up with something that there is no
постоянно придумали что-то что нет
way to hurt and the Americans
возможности ранить а американцы
came up with something that there is a way to
придумали что-то что есть возможность
spread it yeah it's not just us and
распространять Да это не только у нас и
in America and at other times there were such
в Америке и в других моментах были такие
moments that they came up with something It's
моменты то что они что-то придумывали
good that in the Soviet Union they came up with
Хорошо что в Советском Союзе придумали
something that they were able to spread Tesla
такое что смогли распространить Тесла
Tesla you know And you know Let me
Тесла знаешь А ты в курсе Давай тебе
tell you one such thing And you know
скажу Одну одну такую вещь А ты в курсе
that our automobile industry before the war
что у нас автомобилестроение до войны
was the best in the world we had the
было самое лучшая в мире у нас самые
best cars before what war well
лучшие автомобиль до какой войны ну
World War II naturally
Второй мировой естественно
I'm telling you about it you know no that
я тебе про неё говорю ты в курсе нет что
our cars were the best in the
у нас автомобили были лучшие вообще во
whole world even BMW and Mercedes they were
всём мире даже BMW там и Mercedes они
just resting Gru Henry Ford in general
отдыхали просто Гру Генри Форд вообще
now Henry Ford is turning over
сейчас Генри Форд вообще перевернулся
in his grave because you don't believe
сейчас в гробу от того что ты не веришь
it you know Henry Ford took a lot from us
в это понимаешь Генри фрд от нас много
you know tell me which Soviet
взял понимаешь расскажи какие советские
cars were the best one and a half trucks there and
автомобили были самыми лу полуторки там
there ZIL ZIL ZIS there yes
туда Зил Зил ЗИС там да
[music]
[музыка]
let's start with passenger cars Yes Listen No
давай с легковых начнём Да Слушай Нет
I won't tell you the details now
это я тебе сейчас в подробности я тебе
but you Well
не скажу но ты Ну
just Read these like
просто Почитай эти как
they were from that time
они тех времён
Yes yes just tell me if the Soviet
да да просто скажи вот если Советский
Union made the best cars before the
Союз делал самые лучшие автомобили до
war Yes What for example can you
войны Да какой Вот например можешь
tell me what good
назвать мне какой делали хороший
passenger car they made I can't say
легковой автомобиль не могу сказать
because
потому
I wouldn't go into detail at that point ZIS
би я ну не углублялся в этот момент ЗИС
ZIL
ЗИЛ
there Moskvich there or whatever if you
там Москвич там или что там е если ты
look American Yes trucks from those
посмотришь американские Да грузовики тех
years They can still drive Azil
годов Они до сих пор могут ездить Азил
in short you'll drive for 2 years and die
короче тебе 2 года проездить и сдохнет
No you're wrong if well those well those from
Нет ты не прав если бы ну те
those years are still here in the
ну те тех годов до сих пор они у нас в
Soviet Union they make films
советских фильма снимают филь
for films maybe
для фильмов может
suitable Why not so there are only
подходят Почему нет так их осталось-то
a few left good but these Soviet ZILs
единиц хорошо а вот эти советские зилы
here are American Yes cars were sold
вот американские Да машины продавались
all over the world and where did they buy Soviet ZILs
во всём мире а советские зилы куда
so they are from us What do you mean we had a
покупали так они у нас Ты что у нас
ban on their distribution we have
запрет был чтобы их распространять у нас
iron envy you don't understand what's
желез зависть ты не понимаешь что
wrong they didn't sell anywhere maybe
лих никуда не продавали может быть на
they were sold for some kind of export
какой-то экспорт их
sing against the unions  you
продавали пой против союзами
know you're telling me now where
понимаешь Ты мне сейчас говоришь куда-то
someone sold something do you know that
кто-то что-то продавали Ты в курсе что
during the war our GDP
во время войны у нас ВВП
grew
вырос
m you know about this during the Second
м в курсе об этом у нас во время Второй
World War our GDP grew by 2 and
мировой войны у нас ВВП вырос на 2 и с
something percent can you imagine do you
чем-то процентов можешь себе представить
know why why Well because we
знаешь почему почему Ну потому что у нас
mobilized all our production it was
всё производство мобилизовал его
moved from Europe closer to Asia to the Urals
перевезли из Европы ближе к Азии на Урал
there back and forth
там туда-сюда
and all the people were there They mobilized both this and the
и там все люди Они мобилизовали и этот и
GDP for the sake of interest was the Internet invented in the
ВВП ради интереса интернет придумали в
Soviet Union or the Americans Yes I don't know
Советском Союзе или американцы Да зна
where it was invented I don't care I understand
где его придумали мне это неважно понима
drones were invented in the Soviet Union Yes it doesn't
дроны в Советском Союзе придумали Да это
matter understand you
неважно
know what's important it's important who
пойми знаешь что важно важно кто этим
uses it and how they use it
пользуется и как этим пользуется
you understand That's all A It doesn't matter who
понимаешь Вот и всё А Неважно кто это
invented it Or maybe A How do you know who
придумал А может А откуда знаешь кто это
invented it Well let's say DaVa for example
придумал Ну допустим Дава те пример
let's say they invented it It's in America yes And how do you
допустим придумали Это в Америке да А ты
know maybe it was some Russian scientist
откуда знаешь может это русский учёный
defector who invented it Well it
перебежчик какой-нибудь придумал Ну
could be either Chinese or
может такое быть или китайский или
Chinese or Japanese what difference does it make Who
китайский или японский какая разница Кто
invented it you understand what's important is who and how they
его придумал понимаешь важно кто как и
use it now that's all the question
пользуется этим сейчас вот и всё вопрос
well after the collapse of the Soviet Union
хорошо после развала Советского Союза
can you name  some developments of
можешь назвать какие-то разработки
Russia
России
[music]
[музыка]
I'll start from afar you can Come on from
Я тебе сейчас начну издалека можешь
afar
Давай издалека
ok Well I had a Mercedes 124 you
хорошо Да вот у меня был Mercedes 124
know what it is you know Yes let's run already
знаешь что это знаешь Да давай уже бегом
No come on don't rush me You
Нет давай ты меня Не подгоняй Ты же
agreed that I'm from afar you're taking so long I
согласился что я издалека ты так долго Я
want you from afar but you go quickly Come on Well
хочу чтобы ты издалека но ты быстро чтоб
damn you want you agreed with me
шёл Давай Ну блин ты хочешь ты со мной
Why don't you answer for your words
согласился Почему ты за свои слова не
Now I can send you now
отвечаешь Сейчас я могу тебя сейчас ещё
if you will Come on either you speak
послать если будешь Давай либо говоришь
or go Why are you getting
либо идёшь Ты зачем переходишь Ну на
personal What are you bullying do you hear Hello have
личность ты Ты что быкует слышишь ты
you calmed down how did you start
Алло успокоился ты как начал
talking What are you doing what started you bullying What did
говорить Ты что ты что начал быковать Ты
I start closing yes And what are you doing or what
чего я начал Закрыл да А ты что или что
I didn't understand why are you talking like that Well it's more
Я не понял ты что так говоришь Ну так
interesting this way You hear the conversation
интереснее получается Разговор слышишь
everything I mean you're walking and
всё В смысле всё
relaxing oh
идёшь отдыхаешь да
well he's like that Damn it we
ладно такие он такой Блин так
communicated so intellectually on such highly
интеллектуально общались на такие высоко
intellectual topics And here
интеллектуальные темы А тут
Android like Pska comment the best damn
Андройде лайк пска комент лучшее блин
education
образование
P6 on y Telegram right now  axis VN and
П6 на й Telegram прямо зараз ось ВН а
pok ce very and very important YouTube is busy with
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg or in ny ban and very
нас через скарг ор в ньй бан и дуже
many videos I do not show to people at times do not
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams That is why in order for
показуе информация про стрими Тому для
us Mali operational links are
того щоб ми Мали оперативний звязок
written right now and while there are videos in telegram
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
OKM there is also useful information
окм видео ще теж ва и корисна информация
and we understand you
и мы пон вама
interesting links
пой тивный звязок
independently in that chi will show you about
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine write
YouTube Слава Украине пиши